Chitrang Patel

265 Yorkland Blvd, North York, ON M2J 1S5 | +91-8511928411 chitrang200889@gmail.com | https://chitrang200889.github.io/vcard/

Present

Pursuing post graduation in Mobile Application Design and Development Co-op program from Lambton College in Toronto campus. Ready to apply my 4 years of experience in Android and following technologies that I will learn during course work.

- Swift, iOS
- Java, Android
- Cross-Platform and mobile browser apps
- Game and Wearable app development

Technical Skills

- Design Pattern MVP
- Reactive Extension RxAndroid
- Networking Retrofit, OkHttp3, Volley
- Data Parsing JSON, XML, SOAP
- Data storage SQLite, Content Providers, Shared Preferences, External Storage
- Version Control GitHub, Bitbucket, GitLab, SVN

Employment

Sr. Android Developer(Tech Lead)

Nov 2016 - Oct 2017

Valsad, India

- BosLeo Pvt. Ltd.Requirement analysis and project documentation
 - Translated business requirements into working solutions
 - Approached and implemented new technology to maximize product efficiency

Sr. Android Developer(Team Lead)

Sep 2015 - Oct 2016

Dynamic Dreamz Websolutions

Surat, India

- Communicated with client, technical and management team and end users to collect requirements, described software product and its feature and technical details
- Mentored co-workers by reviewing and improving code
- Provided suggestions and feedback to designing team to enrich user experience

Android Developer

Jun 2013 - Aug 2015

Krtya Softwares

Surat, India

- Designed, developed and deployed mobile applications successfully on play store
- Created mock-ups, wire-frames and working prototypes for client-related projects
- Learned development tools android studio, eclipse and android simulators

Education

Post Graduate - Mobile App Design and Development	Present - 2019
Lambton College	Toronto, Canada
Master of Engineering - Computer Science Indian Institute of Science	2012 Bangalore, India

Bachelor of Engineering - Information Technology

2010

LDCE, Gujarat University

Ahmedabad, India